<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/health/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-04-18T14:44:40+02:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/health/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Operative Word | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>by Saket Kulkarni</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Social Distancing Isn’t Enough</title>
      <link href="/virus-load" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Social Distancing Isn't Enough" />
      <published>2020-04-16T17:43:19+02:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-16T17:43:19+02:00</updated>
      <id>/virus-load</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/virus-load">&lt;p&gt;As the COVID-19 pandemic has progressed and people around the world have started to understand the dangers and the virulence of the SARS-CoV-2 virus, social distancing has been one of the mitigating strategies imposed everywhere. This is a highly necessary step in preventing the spread of the virus and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flattenthecurve.com/&quot;&gt;flattening the curve&lt;/a&gt;. However, as some countries appear to be getting the spread of the virus under control there are already sounds about “opening up” certain countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons for “opening up” are myriad but, aside from the &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;discomfort many people seem to feel&lt;/a&gt; at being socially isolated, the biggest driver is probably the state of our economies. The pressure for people who are currently not earning a livelihood &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;is enormous&lt;/a&gt; and the stimulus packages being provided in most countries are either &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;insufficient&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;simply not materializing&lt;/a&gt;. Businesses are &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;already folding&lt;/a&gt; under the financial pressure and if this state of isolation needs to be prolonged, it will only hurt us further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the promising start some countries have made in getting the pandemic under control, the outlook on opening up is &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;still bleak&lt;/a&gt;. It is possible that the there may be multiple waves of COVID-19 in the coming months and even that it may [become endemic]. The concern that this period of isolation may stretch for longer than businesses can tolerate has led to &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;proposals of opening up businesses while respecting social distancing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo attribution: Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/@cottonbro&quot;&gt;cottonbro&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com&quot;&gt;Pexels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Saket Kulkarni</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="COVID" />
      
        <category term="Health" />
      
        <category term="Society" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">As the COVID-19 pandemic has progressed and people around the world have started to understand the dangers and the virulence of the SARS-CoV-2 virus, social distancing has been one of the mitigating strategies imposed everywhere. This is a highly necessary step in preventing the spread of the virus and flattening the curve. However, as some countries appear to be getting the spread of the virus under control there are already sounds about “opening up” certain countries.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
